{

  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Q1. The aqueous solution of which of the following compounds is the best conductor of electric current?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Acetic acid",
        "b": "Hydrochloric acid",
        "c": "Ammonia",
        "d": "Fructose"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      
    },
    {
      "question": "Q2. Which of the following is not an example of an oxidizing agent?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Hydrogen peroxide",
        "b": "Potassium dichromate",
        "c": "Nitric acid",
        "d": "Hydrogen sulphide"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      
    }
	{
      "question": "Q3. Which of the following substances can act as both oxidising and reducing agent?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "KMnO<sub>4</sub>",
        "b": "K<sub>2</sub> Cr<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>",
        "c": " HNO3",
        "d": "H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      
    }
	{
      "question": "Q4. Electrolytes conduct electric current?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "by the movement of ions",
        "b": "by the movement of atoms",
        "c": "by the movement of molecules",
        "d": "by the movement of electrons from the cathode to anode"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      },
      {
      "question": "Q5.  An electrochemical cell generally consists of a cathode and an anode. Which of the following statements is correct with respect to the cathode?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Oxidation occurs at the cathode",
        "b": "Electrons move into the cathode",
        "c": "Usually denoted by a negative sign",
        "d": "Is usually made up of insulating material"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      },
	  {
      "question": "Q6. Which of the following is not a type of electrochemical cell?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Oxidation occurs at the cathode",
        "b": "Electrons move into the cathode",
        "c": "Usually denoted by a negative sign",
        "d": "Is usually made up of insulating material"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      },
	  {
      "question": "Q7. Which of the following is not a generally used electrolyte in the salt bridges used to connect the two half-cells of an electrochemical cell?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "NaCl",
        "b": "KNO<sub>3</sub>",
        "c": "KCl",
        "d": "ZnSO<sub>4</sub>"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      },
	  {
      "question": "Q8.The reductant may be defined as a substance, whose oxidation no of the atom?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " increases",
        "b": "decreases",
        "c": "remains constant",
        "d": "may increases or decreases"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      },
	  {
      "question": "Q9.The chemical NaOH which is used in the manufacture of soaps, detergents, papers etc. is prepared by the electric current in?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "aqueous NaCl",
        "b": "molten NaCl",
        "c": " H<sub>2</sub>O",
        "d": "aqueous KCI"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      },
	  {
      "question": "Q10. Which of the following is not a good conductor?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cu",
        "b": " NaCl (aq)",
        "c": "NaCl (molten)",
        "d": "NaCl(s)"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      }
      
    }
  ]

}
